EMILIO GONZALEZ

Senior Java Full Stack Developer

352-507-6561

@ emilio.gonzalez.dev@gmail.com

West Allis, WI

SUMMARY

A senior Full-Stack Developer with solid experience in various industries, with strong proficiency in technologies such as Java, Spring, Scala, Python, Diango, React, AWS

I'm passionate about solving complex problems across projects and focus on ensuring the best quality and fast delivery of time

EXPERIENCE

Senior Java Full stack Developer

The Trade Desk

苗 2022 - 2024 👂 Ventura, CA

Developed internal monitoring tools, customer facing services, internal dashboard, ad management platform increasing user engagement by 30%

- Designed and implemented 4 back-end applications using Java, Spring MVC, Spring Security, Hibernate, and JPA
- Designed, developed, and maintained RESTful APIs using Spring Boot framework to support web and mobile applications
- Implemented 20+ features in 5 React SPAs with TypeScript, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, GraphQL, and refactored AngularJS codebase
- Implemented asynchronous processing using Spring's support for messaging systems such as RabbitMQ and Apache Kafka
- Took part in all steps of the agile SDLC(Software Development Life Cycle) utilizing Jira and Confluence
- Led regular code reviews in GitHub, providing constructive feedback to team members to ensure high-quality code

Java Back-End Developer

Walmart, Inc

2020 - 2022 O Hoboken, NJ

Built industry defining reusable customer and partner facing services and products to lead differentiated experiences and revenue

- Built the platform in Java and Scala, Spark Streaming and SQL, Oracle, Kafka, Docker, and Redshift, running on Kubernetes on AWS
- Developed and deployed backend services, such as microservices with Spring Boot, Spring Batch for various of platforms
- Leveraged Core Java concepts such as object-oriented programming, multithreading, and collections to implement business logic
- Integrated third-party APIs and services into Java and Scala applications, ensuring seamless communication and data exchange
- Refactored legacy Java codebase to Scala, ensuring compatibility with new language features and APIs
- Streamlined application deployment in collaboration with 40+ team members by implementing a CI/CD pipeline using Git, Jenkins, CircleCI

Software Developer

Solvelt

苗 2016 - 2020 👂 Lafayette, LA

Initiated 10+ projects from scratch across Finance, E-commerce, and Healthcare industries, with technologies like ReactJS, Java, and Spring Boot

- Designed, implemented and maintained SEO friendly and responsive web applications with HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, React
- Engineered scalable and extensible backend services and REST APIs using technologies such as Java, Spring Boot, Node.js, ExpressJS
- Ensured backend performance through optimization of PL/SQL queries, caching mechanisms, and deployment of efficient algorithms
- Integrated third-party services into back-end infrastructure using Node.js, GraphQL, Express.js, and MongoDB in 10+ web applications
- Conducted test-driven development (TDD) practices, writing unit tests and A/B tests with Jest, Cypress, JUnit, Mockito, Selenium
- Crafted and Deployed a greatly optimized REST API from analysis of existing project

SKILLS

Languages

Scala **Python JavaScript** Java SQL **GraphQL** HTMI /CSS

Frameworks & libraries

Spring Boot Hibernate Django **Angular** Node.js React Next.is Storage **MySQL** MongoDB **PostgreSQL DynamoDB** Oracle Cassandra Tools & Platforms Git **Jenkins** Docker **AWS** GCP Mayen Gradle Azure

PROJECTS

Ad Management Platform

ii 10/2022 - 12/2022 Ventura, CA

Built a strong backend and web-based interfaces using Angular, Java, Spring Boot

E-commerce Platform

iii 11/2017 - 02/2018 ♀ Lafayette, LA Built an e-commerce platform from scratch using the React, Next.js, Node.js, Spring Boot

EDUCATION

Marguette University

B.S. in Computer Science

GPA 3.9 / 4.0

苗 2012 - 2016 👂 Milwaukee, WI

CERTIFICATIONS

Advanced JavaScript

Learned advanced programming concepts.

Cloud Architecture with AWS

A comprehensive course provided by AWS